<item>
	<title>illegal and contradictory domain activities</title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/illegal-and-contradictory-domain-activities</link>
	<pubDate>Thu Aug 12 21:44:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Security"><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Web+Development"><![CDATA[Web Development]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/illegal-and-contradictory-domain-activities</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-08-12/aFipBCxFuICEikdJkyEJaJAJEHnbmhHqknqbxzpCnEzxhmCAfoHIxxjmCDrd/ccofworld.jpg"><img alt="Ccofworld" src="http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-08-12/aFipBCxFuICEikdJkyEJaJAJEHnbmhHqknqbxzpCnEzxhmCAfoHIxxjmCDrd/ccofworld.jpg" /></a>
</div>
<strong>Domain parking</strong></p>
<p>is the registration of an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet" title="Internet">Internet</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain name</a> without using it for services such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E-mail" class="mw-redirect" title="E-mail">e-mail</a> or a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Website" title="Website">website</a>. This may be done to reserve the domain name for future development, to protect against the possibility of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cybersquatting" title="Cybersquatting">cybersquatting</a>, or to engage in cybersquatting. Since the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_registrar" title="Domain name registrar">domain name registrar</a> will have set <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name_server" title="Name server">name servers</a> for the domain, the registrar or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_reseller" class="mw-redirect" title="Domain name reseller">reseller</a> potentially has use of the domain rather than the final registrant. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_parking">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_parking</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Domain name warehousing</strong></p>
<p>is the common practice of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_registrar" title="Domain name registrar">registrars</a> obtaining control of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain names</a> with the intent to hold or &ldquo;warehouse&rdquo; names for their use and/or profit. Also see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_front_running" title="Domain name front running">domain name front running</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_tasting" title="Domain tasting">domain tasting</a>, related business practices employed by registrants.</p>
<p>Typically this practice occurs after a domain name has expired and  the previous owner (registrant) has not exercised his/her right to renew  that name within the allotted time frame (approximately 45 days  following expiration). Domain's expiration date and time are easily  calculated based on the expiration date in the whois and the redemption  process. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_warehousing">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_warehousing</a> )<!--more--></p>
<p><strong>Domain tasting</strong></p>
<p>is the practice of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain name</a> registrant using the five-day "grace period" (the Add Grace Period or AGP) at the beginning of the registration of an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICANN" title="ICANN">ICANN</a>-regulated <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second-level_domain" title="Second-level domain">second-level domain</a> to test the marketability of the domain. During this period, when a registration must be fully refunded by the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_registry" title="Domain name registry">domain name registry</a>, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cost-benefit_analysis" title="Cost-benefit analysis">cost-benefit analysis</a> is conducted by the registrant on the viability of deriving income from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_marketing" title="Internet marketing">advertisements</a> being placed on the domain's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Website" title="Website">website</a>. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_tasting">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_tasting</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Domain name front running</strong></p>
<p>is the practice whereby a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_registrar" title="Domain name registrar">domain name registrar</a> uses insider information to register domains for the purpose of  re-selling them or earning revenue via ads placed on the domain's  landing page. By registering the domains, the registrar locks out other  potential registrars from selling the domain to a customer. The  registrar typically takes advantage of the 5-day "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_tasting" title="Domain tasting">domain tasting</a>" trial period, where the domain can be locked without payment. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_front_running">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_front_running</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Typosquatting</strong>, also called <strong>URL hijacking</strong></p>
<p>is a form of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cybersquatting" title="Cybersquatting">cybersquatting</a> which relies on mistakes such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typographical_error" title="Typographical error">typographical errors</a> made by Internet users when inputting a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Url" class="mw-redirect" title="Url">website address</a> into a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser" title="Web browser">web browser</a>.  Should a user accidentally enter an incorrect website address, they may  be led to an alternative website owned by a cybersquatter.</p>
<h2><span class="mw-headline" style="font-size: small;">"Catchall" typosquatting</span></h2>
<p>In addition to purchases of individual domain name, several attempts  have been made by larger corporations to profit from users' typos by  redirecting them without their knowledge.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Microsoft" title="Microsoft">Microsoft</a>'s <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Internet_Explorer" title="Internet Explorer">Internet Explorer</a> automatically redirects users' mistyped URL queries to their <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/MSN_Search" class="mw-redirect" title="MSN Search">MSN Search</a> page. Though a user can reconfigure their browser to use a different search tool, <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Google" title="Google">Google</a>, one of MSN's biggest rivals, is not in the list. However, on their <a href="http://www.google.com/options/defaults.html" class="external text" title="http://www.google.com/options/defaults.html" rel="nofollow">web site</a>, Google has explained how to make their search engine the IE default for mistyped urls.</li>
<li>In 2003, <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Top-level_domain" title="Top-level domain">top-level domain</a> registry operator <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/VeriSign" title="VeriSign">VeriSign</a>'s <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Site_Finder" title="Site Finder">Site Finder</a> automatically redirected traffic sent to unregistered domains. This  caused a fair amount of outrage from the Internet standards community,  and an emergency patch to <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/BIND" title="BIND">BIND</a> was issued to circumvent VeriSign's actions. VeriSign disabled the service after only three weeks. ( <a href="http://www.enotes.com/topic/Typosquatting#">http://www.enotes.com/topic/Typosquatting#</a>.22Catchall.22_typosquatting )</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Reverse domain name hijacking</strong> (also known as <strong>reverse cybersquatting</strong>)</p>
<p>occurs where a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trademark" title="Trademark">trademark</a> owner attempts to secure a domain name by making false <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cybersquatting" title="Cybersquatting">cybersquatting</a> claims against a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain name</a>&rsquo;s rightful owner.<sup class="reference"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_domain_hijacking#cite_note-0"></a></sup>This often intimidates domain name owners into transferring ownership  of their domain names to trademark owners to avoid legal action,  particularly when the domain names belong to smaller organizations or  individuals. Reverse domain name hijacking is most commonly perpetrated by larger corporations and famous individuals.<sup class="reference"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_domain_hijacking#cite_note-2"></a></sup></p>
<p>Reverse domain name hijacking is an analogue to the practice of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_hijacking" title="Domain hijacking">domain hijacking</a>,  wherein domain name registrants registered domain names containing  famous third party trademarks with the intent of profiting by selling  the domain names back to trademark owners.<sup class="reference"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_domain_hijacking#cite_note-3"></a></sup>Trademark owners initially responded by filing cybersquatting lawsuits against registrants to enforce their trademark rights.  However, as the number of cybersquatting incidents grew, trademark  owners noticed that registrants would often settle their cases rather  than litigate.Consequently, although the filing of cybersquatting lawsuits began as a  defensive strategy to combat cybersquatting, such lawsuits also can be  used as a way of strongarming innocent domain name registrants into  giving up domain names that the trademark owner is not, in fact,  entitled to. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_domain_hijacking">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_domain_hijacking</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Domain name speculation</strong></p>
<p>is the practice of identifying and registering or acquiring <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet" title="Internet">Internet</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain names</a> with the intent of selling them later for a profit.</p>
<p>The main targets of domain name speculation are generic words which can be valuable for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type-in_traffic" title="Type-in traffic">type-in traffic</a> and for the dominant position they would have in any field due to their descriptive nature. Hence generic words and phrases such as <em>poker</em>, <em>insurance</em>, <em>travel</em>, <em>creditcards</em>, <em>sex</em> and others are attractive targets of domain speculation in any <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-level_domain" title="Top-level domain">top-level domain</a>.</p>
<p>The speculative characteristics of domain names may be linked to news  reports or current events. However, the effective period during which  such opportunities exist may be limited. Quick turnaround in the resale  of domains is often called <em>domain <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flipping" title="Flipping">flipping</a></em>.</p>
<p><strong>Domain sniping</strong></p>
<p>is the practice of an individual registering a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain name</a> whose registration has lapsed in the immediate moments after expiry. This practice has largely been rendered moot through <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICANN" title="ICANN">ICANN</a>'s addition of the <strong>Redemption Grace Period</strong> (RGP), which allows registrants 30 days to reclaim their domain name.  By law there are no perpetual rights to domain names after payment of  registration fees lapses, aside from trademark rights granted by common  law or statute. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_sniping">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_sniping</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Fast flux</strong></p>
<p>is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_system" class="mw-redirect" title="Domain name system">DNS</a> technique used by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Botnet" title="Botnet">botnets</a> to hide <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phishing" title="Phishing">phishing</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malware" title="Malware">malware</a> delivery sites behind an ever-changing network of compromised hosts acting as proxies. It can also refer to the combination of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer-to-peer_networking" class="mw-redirect" title="Peer-to-peer networking">peer-to-peer networking</a>, distributed command and control, web-based <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Load_balancing_%28computing%29" title="Load balancing (computing)">load balancing</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proxy_server" title="Proxy server">proxy</a> redirection used to make malware networks more resistant to discovery and counter-measures. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storm_Worm" title="Storm Worm">Storm Worm</a> is one of the recent malware variants to make use of this technique. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_flux">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_flux</a> )</p>
<p><strong>Domain hack</strong> (sometimes known as a <strong>domain name hack</strong>)</p>
<p>is an unconventional <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name" title="Domain name">domain name</a> that combines domain levels, especially the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-level_domain" title="Top-level domain">top-level domain</a> (TLD), to spell out the full "name" or title of the domain.<sup class="reference"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_hack#cite_note-domainhacks-0"></a></sup> Well-known examples include <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blo.gs" title="Blo.gs">blo.gs</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Del.icio.us" class="mw-redirect" title="Del.icio.us">del.icio.us</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cr.yp.to" class="mw-redirect" title="Cr.yp.to">cr.yp.to</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Retou.ch&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1" class="new" title="Retou.ch (page does not exist)">retou.ch</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goo.gl" class="mw-redirect" title="Goo.gl">goo.gl</a>.</p>
<p>In this context, the "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hack" title="Hack">hack</a>" represents a trick (as in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_programming" title="Computer programming">programming</a>), not an exploit or break-in (as in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_security" title="Computer security">security</a>). ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_hack">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_hack</a> )</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Domain parking is the registration of an Internet domain name without using it for services such as e-mail or a website. This may be done to reserve the domain name for future development, to protect against the possibility of cybersquatting, or t...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu Aug 12 21:44:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu Aug 12 21:44:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>25609718</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>illegal-and-contradictory-domain-activities</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>8192110</wp:comment_id>
			
				<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[MagnusT]]></wp:comment_author>
				<wp:comment_author_url><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author_url>
			
			<wp:comment_date>Mon Apr 18 23:24:17 -0700 2011</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>Mon Apr 18 23:24:17 -0700 2011</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for this catalog.  It is a very well written compendium.

&quot;Redemption&quot; is legalized cyber-squatting and it must end.  Domain Name Registration should work more akin to the patent system.  One registrar, first to file, held for 10 years (e.g.) instead of just 1, registered domains is distributed via flat file from .gov website and propagated appropriately.  The registree must file for a renewal of the registration before or by the expiration date in order to secure the domain name for an additional ten years or else the first to file after the expiration date gets the domain.  Domains can be renewed into perpetuity b y corporations, or willed to heirs, just as any tangible property, etc.  The current system is stupid and creates a legalized form of extortion to be practiced by a privileged few.

I suggest you write a letter of complaint to ICANN if you feel strongly enough about this issue.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
		</wp:comment>
	
</item>
