<item>
	<title>Even a database has REST API !! (CouchDB)</title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/even-a-database-has-rest-api-couchdb</link>
	<pubDate>Sun Aug 22 11:01:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Cloud+Computing"><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="RESTful"><![CDATA[RESTful]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Web+Development"><![CDATA[Web Development]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/even-a-database-has-rest-api-couchdb</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-08-21/JxIfoJsirAkGrryipCbnDbxhJaCkhfwfIyyzpbbJdsjCwubjcjxqrrwsvAwd/couch_arch_scale3.png"><img alt="Couch_arch_scale3" src="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-08-21/JxIfoJsirAkGrryipCbnDbxhJaCkhfwfIyyzpbbJdsjCwubjcjxqrrwsvAwd/couch_arch_scale3.png" /></a>
</div>
What CouchDB is</h2>
<ul>
<li>A document database server, accessible via a RESTful JSON API.</li>
<li>Ad-hoc and schema-free with a flat address space.</li>
<li>Distributed, featuring robust, incremental replication with bi-directional  conflict detection and management.</li>
<li>Query-able and index-able, featuring a table oriented reporting engine that  uses JavaScript as a query language.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What it is Not</h2>
<ul>
<li>A relational database.</li>
<li>A replacement for relational databases.</li>
<li>An object-oriented database. Or more specifically, meant to function as a  seamless persistence layer for an OO programming language.<!--more--></li>
</ul>
<h2>Key Characteristics</h2>
<h3>Documents</h3>
<p>A CouchDB document is an object that consists of named fields. Field  values may be strings, numbers, dates, or even ordered lists and  associative maps. An  example of a document would be a blog post:</p>
<p><em>"Subject": "I like Plankton" &nbsp;</em><br /><em>"Author": "Rusty" &nbsp;</em><br /><em>"PostedDate": "5/23/2006" &nbsp;</em><br /><em>"Tags": ["plankton", "baseball", "decisions"]</em><br /><em>"Body": "I decided today that I don't like baseball. I like plankton."</em></p>
<p>In the above example document, <code>Subject</code> is a field that contains a single  string value &ldquo;I like plankton&rdquo;. <code>Tags</code> is a field containing the list of values &ldquo;plankton&rdquo;,  &ldquo;baseball&rdquo;, and &ldquo;decisions&rdquo;.</p>
<p>A CouchDB database is a flat collection of these documents. Each document is  identified by a unique ID.</p>
<h3>Views</h3>
<p>To address this problem of adding structure back to semi-structured data,  CouchDB integrates a view model using JavaScript for description. Views are the  method of aggregating and reporting on the documents in a database, and are  built on-demand to aggregate, join and report on database documents. Views are  built dynamically and don&rsquo;t affect the underlying document, you can have as  many different view representations of the same data as you like.</p>
<h3>Schema-Free</h3>
<p>Unlike SQL databases which are designed to store and report on highly  structured, interrelated data, CouchDB is designed to store and report on large  amounts of semi-structured, document oriented data. CouchDB greatly simplifies  the development of document oriented applications, which make up the bulk of  collaborative web applications.</p>
<p>In an SQL database, as needs evolve the schema and storage of the existing data  must be updated. This often causes problems as new needs arise that simply  weren&rsquo;t anticipated in the initial database designs, and makes distributed  &ldquo;upgrades&rdquo; a problem for every host that needs to go through a schema update.</p>
<p>With CouchDB, no schema is enforced, so new document types with new meaning can  be safely added alongside the old. The view engine, using JavaScript, is  designed to easily handle new document types and disparate but similar  documents.</p>
<h3>Distributed</h3>
<p>CouchDB is a peer based distributed database system. Any number of CouchDB  hosts (servers and offline-clients) can have independent &ldquo;replica copies&rdquo; of  the same database, where applications have full database interactivity (query,  add, edit, delete). When back online or on a schedule, database changes are  replicated bi-directionally.</p>
<p>CouchDB has built-in conflict detection and management and the replication  process is incremental and fast, copying only documents and individual fields  changed since the previous replication. Most applications require no special  planning to take advantage of distributed updates and replication.</p>
<p>Unlike cumbersome attempts to bolt distributed features on top of the same  legacy models and databases, it is the result of careful ground-up design,  engineering and integration. The document, view, security and replication  models, the special purpose query language, the efficient and robust disk  layout are all carefully integrated for a reliable and efficient system.</p>
<p>via <a href="http://couchdb.apache.org/docs/intro.html">http://couchdb.apache.org/docs/intro.html</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[What CouchDB is A document database server, accessible via a RESTful JSON API. Ad-hoc and schema-free with a flat address space. Distributed, featuring robust, incremental replication with bi-directional conflict detection and management. Query-ab...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Sun Aug 22 11:01:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Aug 22 11:01:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>26261697</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>even-a-database-has-rest-api-couchdb</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
