<item>
	<title>SparxUp Awards 2010 : Awarding Night </title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/sparxup-awards-2010-awarding-night</link>
	<pubDate>Wed Oct 06 00:51:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Events"><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Startups"><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/sparxup-awards-2010-awarding-night</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-06/fDufvwhelrwqdkclFpftCgJGgBzHAcIdxcvdmdydiBDfxDdvADalwrkixund/sparxup.png"><img alt="Sparxup" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-06/fDufvwhelrwqdkclFpftCgJGgBzHAcIdxcvdmdydiBDfxDdvADalwrkixund/sparxup.png" /></a>
</div>
SparxUp Awards 2010 is the biggest and most significant tech   startup event in Indonesia, remarks the birth of a new era of tech   industry in Indonesia. Hosted by DailySocial.net, SemutApi Colony and   Kompas.com, as the contribution to move the tech industry forward.</p>
<p>SparxUp Awards 2010 is an appreciation night for Indonesian   startups and their contribution to the tech industry. We have one   objective : to show the world how Indonesian tech-industry has grown   and can significantly contribute to moving the world forward through technology.</p>
<p>The event chain started back in August 2010 where tech   entrepreneurs are encouraged to submit their startups to participate   in the startup competition. The second round of events include 3   workshops special for startup owners where we invite speakers to share   materials about User Interface Design, Scaling, Optimization and   Virtualization and also Startups Business 101. These workshops will   give participants some insights about their service and optimize it   during the process. After the workshops are done, participants are   filtered judged from their proposal slides sent to our judges and come   up with 50 finalists that will do a live pitch session in front of our   judges. Founders are a significant part of a startup, we believe good   founders and a good team is essential, that's why we have to do a live   pitch session.</p>
<p>The last round of events is closed by the Awarding Night on   November 6th where 24 winners from 8 categories will do a quick pitch   session (3 minutes each) in front of the audience. For the grand   finale, SparxUp Awards 2010 will announce Best of The Best and Rising   Star winners from these 24 winners.</p>
<p>SparxUp Awards 2010 is not an event you want to miss. It's the   biggest startup event in Indonesia, a start of a golden age of   Indonesian startups and tech Industry.</p>
<p><em> <strong style="font-size: 16px;">Event Details</strong> </em></p>
<p><strong>Date : November 6th 2010</strong></p>
<p><strong>Time : 7pm - 10pm</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue : FX Lifestyle X'nter , Jakarta</strong></p>
<div style="font-size: 12px;"><em> <span style="font-size: 16px;"> <strong>Tickets</strong> </span> </em>
<p>The ticket price for this event is USD$ 0 or IDR 0,- a.k.a <strong>FREE!!</strong> :-p</p>
</div>
<p>via : <a href="http://www.amiando.com/sparxup.html">http://www.amiando.com/sparxup.html</a><strong><br /></strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[SparxUp Awards 2010 is the biggest and most significant tech startup event in Indonesia, remarks the birth of a new era of tech industry in Indonesia. Hosted by DailySocial.net, SemutApi Colony and Kompas.com, as the contribution to move the tech ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Wed Oct 06 00:51:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Wed Oct 06 00:51:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>29798390</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>sparxup-awards-2010-awarding-night</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
