<item>
	<title>RSA Conference 2011</title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/rsa-conference-2011</link>
	<pubDate>Tue Oct 12 11:16:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Cryptography"><![CDATA[Cryptography]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Events"><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Security"><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/rsa-conference-2011</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-12/CjrBfynkHDdCIvAeyqCaBuvadzixrizjopoEJjemcEeyyuFududIDybGhfgJ/logorsa.gif"><img alt="Logorsa" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-12/CjrBfynkHDdCIvAeyqCaBuvadzixrizjopoEJjemcEeyyuFududIDybGhfgJ/logorsa.gif" /></a>
</div>
RSA Conference continues to play an integral role in keeping security  professionals across the globe connected and educated. The focus on  cyberthreats grows each day and RSA Conference is the educational and  training environment to prepare you to meet these challenges head-on. Be  sure to attend RSA Conference 2011 from February 14-18, 2011 in San  Francisco.</p>
<p>This has been 20 years since the first conference . Here are the history and milestone :<!--more--></p>
<h2>2009</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Edgar Allen Poe</strong></span></li>
</ul>
<h2>2008</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Alan Mathison Turing</strong></span></li>
<li> In January, Iron Mountain  says it cannot find a  backup tape that belongs to GE Money. The tape contains  the personal  information of about 65,000 J.C. Penney and 100 other retailers&rsquo;   customers </li>
<li> In February, an unencrypted backup tape containing   the social security numbers and bank account information of 4.5 million  Bank of  New York Mellon customers goes missing after being sent to a  storage facility </li>
<li> In March, Hannaford Bros. falls victim to a  targeted  malware attack that exposes some four million credit and debit card   numbers to identity thieves</li>
<li> In March, 13 employees at UCLA Medical   Center are  suspended for  snooping in the confidential medical records of pop star  Britney Spears, who  had been recently hospitalized in the hospital&rsquo;s  psychiatric ward</li>
<li> In June, two men are charged with making  withdrawals  from New York City ATMs totaling $750,000. They used information  from a  previous computer intrusion into a Citibank server that processes ATM   withdrawals</li>
<li> In July, Terry Childs, former network administer  for  the City of San Francisco, is jailed after essentially holding the  city&rsquo;s  network hostage by changing the administrative passwords on the  network's  switches and routers and then refusing to divulge them</li>
<li> In July, Dan Kaminskyiscovers a flaw in the  Internet's Domain  Name System prompting more than 80 software and  hardware vendors to release a  coordinated patch</li>
<li> In August, a former Countrywide Financial Corp.   senior financial analyst, Rene Rebollo, is arrested and charged by the  FBI for  stealing and selling sensitive personal information of an  estimated 2 million  mortgage loan applicants</li>
<li> In August, before bombs dropped on the country of  Georgia, Russia  attacks Georgia&rsquo;s  Internet infrastructure by  coordinating barrages of millions of distributed  denial of service  (D.D.O.S) attacks that overload and effectively shut down  Georgian  servers</li>
<li> In August, a presentation about vulnerabilities in   the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority ticketing system is  banned from  the DEFCON security conference by a court order after the  MBTA protested</li>
<li> In September, vice presidential candidate Sarah   Palin has her personal Yahoo e-mail account hacked during a controversy   regarding her alleged use of private e-mail for state business</li>
<li> In October, Microsoft  issues an emergency patch to  repair a critical Windows server service  vulnerability that leaves  Windows systems dangerously open to attack</li>
<li> In November, the Identity Theft   Resource Center   reports 585 data breaches that exposed over 33 million personal records,  a 31  percent rise over 2007</li>
<li> In November, RSA identifies a single Trojan that   intercepted more than 500,000 online banking account credentials, credit  cards  and other resources</li>
</ul>
<h2>2007</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Leon Batista Alberti</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference attracts over 17,000 attendees</li>
<li>Storm botnet hits 1.6 million PCs, becomes the largest malware headache of the year and makes the most headlines</li>
<li>Connecticut teacher Julie Amero convicted of "risk of injury to a minor" due to spyware infected computers on campus</li>
<li>iPhone launches with much fanfare -- gets hacked</li>
<li>Deadline for PCI and HSPD-12 compliance</li>
<li>TJX breach reports theft of 45.6 million credit and debit cards; results in $41 million payout to banks</li>
<li>Insider at DuPont pleads guilty to stealing $400 million in trade secrets</li>
<li>TD Ameritrade database of 6.3 million customers hacked</li>
<li>Disgruntled ex-UBS PaineWebber employee convicted of a felony for a logic bomb planted in former employer's network<br /> U.S. Department of Energy's Counterintelligence  Directorate -- which is charged with protecting sensitive data and  operations against espionage by foreign entities -- loses 20 computers  that may contain classified data</li>
<li>Series of cyberattacks on various U.S. laboratories  and institutions, cybercriminals have broken into computers at the  Department of Energy's Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) and also  reportedly targeted Los Alamos National Laboratory and Lawrence  Livermore National Laboratory</li>
<li>Database analyst at Certegy Check Services steals  financial data of 8.5 million customers -- later pleads guilty to  federal fraud charges</li>
</ul>
<h2>2006</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Modern Codes in Ancient Sutras</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference celebrates its 15th year</li>
<li>Choice Point fined $15 Million by the FTC for lax security policies</li>
</ul>
<h2>2005</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Codes of Prohibition: Rumrunners and Elizabeth Friedman</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference attracts 14,605 attendees</li>
<li>The first MMS (multimedia messaging service) worm is discovered</li>
<li>The year is peppered with high profile announcementsof data  disclosure breaches (ChoicePoint, Citigroup, Time Warner and Bank of  America)</li>
<li>Trojan.PSPBrick is discovered - the first Trojan horse targeting Sony PlayStation Portable</li>
<li>California passes laws aimed at stopping phishing exploits</li>
<li>U.S. Real ID Act passed</li>
<li>CERT: 5,990 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>2004</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Chinese Remainder Theorem</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference attracts 10,489 attendees; Bill Gates first appearance as keynote speaker</li>
<li>Sasser worm is discovered</li>
<li>Security firm hires teenage Sasser virus writer</li>
<li>Against All Enemies by Richard Clarke hits stores</li>
<li>First anti-spyware law enacted in the U.S. (Utah)</li>
<li>Cabir, the first mobile device worm, is developed</li>
<li>CERT: 3,780 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>2003</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>The Secrets of the Maya</strong></span></li>
<li>MS Blaster and So Big viruses cause over $3.5 Billion in damages</li>
<li>California enacts the nation's first breach notification law  requiring companies to disclose if there have been any breaches of  customers' personal data</li>
<li>Microsoft offers $250,000 reward for culprits of MS Blaster and So Big</li>
<li>Japan passes Personal Information Protection Law</li>
<li>U.S. government passes CAN-SPAM Act to prevent the use of false header information in email</li>
<li>CERT: 3,784 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>&nbsp;</h2>
<h2>2002</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Mary, Queen of Scots</strong></span></li>
<li>First RSA Conference Japan in Tokyo</li>
<li>Growth in Internet fraud outpaces growth of the Internet</li>
<li>Multiple SNMP vulnerabilities are reported; according to CERT the products of more than 100 vendors may be at risk</li>
<li>CERT reports the users of IRC and IM are being tricked into downloading malicious software</li>
<li>Sarbanes Oxley Act passed</li>
<li>33% of ISPs say information security "not a priority"</li>
<li>CERT: 4,129 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>2001</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Search for Extra-Terrestrial Intelligence (SETI)</strong></span></li>
<li>Pat Benatar performs at RSA Conference</li>
<li>The Ramen worm is discovered as it exploits well know Linux vulnerabilities</li>
<li>The Code Red worm is discovered</li>
<li>Hackers attack the White House web site causing a Denial of Service attack</li>
<li>Viruses estimated to cost industry over $13 Billion in 2001</li>
<li>AES announced</li>
<li>43 Nation Council of Europe adopts controversial Cybercrime Treaty</li>
<li>CERT: 2,437 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>2000</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Ancient Greece/Fall of Troy</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference attracts 7,507 attendees; Jefferson Starship performs</li>
<li>First RSA Conference Europe in Munich.</li>
<li>Hackers deemed terrorists under UK Law (Terrorism Act 2000)</li>
<li>FBI continues to hunt hackers with Carnivore tool</li>
<li>Love Bug virus cripples computer worldwide; Love Bug suspect apprehended and later released in the Philippines</li>
<li>Denial of Service attacks shut down Yahoo!, Buy.com, Amazon, eBay, and CNN</li>
<li>Palm.Liberty.A is discovered as the first known Trojan horse for Palm OS</li>
<li>U.S. relaxes encryption export policy</li>
<li>The Electronic Signature in Global &amp; National Commerce Act passed</li>
<li>Teenage hacker Mafiaboy cripples leading Internet sites causing $1.7 Billion in damages</li>
<li>FBI apprehends teenage hacker Coolio, who hijacked and defaced leading web sites</li>
<li>CERT: 1,090 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>1999</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Norse/Viking Runestones</strong></span></li>
<li>Melissa virus released and spreads worldwide</li>
<li>Distribute.net breaks DES during RSA Conference in 22hrs 15mins</li>
<li>CERT: 417 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>1998</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>16th Century monk, Trithemius and his book Polygraphia</strong></span></li>
<li>Skipjack algorithm declassified</li>
<li>Denial of Service attacks hit NASA, U.S. Navy and many universities</li>
<li>U.S. DMCA (Digital Millennium Copyright Act) passed</li>
<li>CERT: 262 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>1997</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Cher Ami, Carrier Pigeon</strong></span></li>
<li>RSA Conference attracts 1,846 attendees</li>
<li>U.S. debate over the export of products containing strong encryption heats up with the SAFE Act</li>
</ul>
<h2>1996</h2>
<ul>
<li>RSA Conference Theme:&nbsp; <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>WWII Navajo Code-Talkers</strong></span></li>
<li>Second edition of Bruce Schneier's Applied Cryptography published</li>
<li>A survey by Dan Farmer finds that 2/3 of "interesting" web sites  such as banks, newspapers and government systems have serious security  flaws</li>
<li>HIPAA enacted; requires healthcare organizations take extra steps to secure personal information</li>
<li>The General Accounting Office publishes a report on  government-wide information security issues finding that security at  most U.S. government agencies is poor</li>
<li>CERT: 345 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>1995</h2>
<ul>
<li>First RSA Conference Theme: <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Egyptian Scarab Seals</strong></span></li>
<li>A leading U.S. bank hacked by Russian attackers transferring  over $10 Million to separate accounts around the world using a laptop  computer</li>
<li>Kevin Mitnick arrested in North Carolina</li>
<li>Hackers alter the web sites of U.S. Justice Department, CIA and the U.S. Air Force</li>
<li>Strict EU data protection and privacy laws enacted</li>
<li>First network vulnerability scanner developed (SATAN: Security Administration Tool for Analyzing Networks)</li>
<li>CERT: 171 vulnerabilities reported</li>
</ul>
<h2>1994</h2>
<ul>
<li>Netscape invents SSL</li>
<li>Clipper Chip announced by the White House</li>
<li>IBM, GE &amp; NBC all hacked over Thanksgiving weekend by a group called "The Internet Liberation Front"</li>
</ul>
<h2>1993</h2>
<ul>
<li>Second, now annual, RSA Conference held</li>
<li>First Fast Software Encryption Conference is held - this event  helps drive the research activities on encryption algorithms that  eventually led to the Advanced Encryption Standard</li>
<li>Cryptographic security/digital signatures for EDI debated</li>
<li>Skipjack algorithm is proposed for key escrow applications (but not published)</li>
<li>Traffic on the web expands at an annual rate of 341,634%</li>
<li>First edition of Bruce Schneier's Applied Cryptography published</li>
</ul>
<h2>1992</h2>
<ul>
<li>Key escrow debate brewing - U.S. government seeking repository for cryptographic keys</li>
<li>Concerns about DES vulnerabilities and possible replacements publicly debated (DSS or RSA/PKCS</li>
</ul>
<h2>NOVEMBER 1991</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>First RSA<sup> </sup>Conference (then called  "Cryptography, Standards &amp; Public Policy") held in Hotel Sofitel in  Redwood City with 50 attendees: the "Conference" starts at 9:00 a.m. and  ends at 3:00 p.m.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: large;">Go to this page to register</span></strong> : <a href="http://www.rsaconference.com/2011/usa/registration.htm">http://www.rsaconference.com/2011/usa/registration.htm</a></p>
<div>
<p>via <a href="http://www.rsaconference.com/2011/usa/index.htm" target="_blank">RSA Conference</a></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[RSA Conference continues to play an integral role in keeping security professionals across the globe connected and educated. The focus on cyberthreats grows each day and RSA Conference is the educational and training environment to prepare you to ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue Oct 12 11:16:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Tue Oct 12 11:16:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>30330641</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>rsa-conference-2011</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
