<item>
	<title>Developer Advocate at Google</title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/developer-advocate-at-google</link>
	<pubDate>Thu Oct 28 11:51:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Google"><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Web+Development"><![CDATA[Web Development]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/developer-advocate-at-google</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-28/kpDEuJyAACgArImJfJmmAyxolAylofvrhgjBFulGrptulqiGwGcsEhdxdbgJ/accent_engatwork-o.jpg"><img alt="Accent_engatwork-o" src="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-10-28/kpDEuJyAACgArImJfJmmAyxolAylofvrhgjBFulGrptulqiGwGcsEhdxdbgJ/accent_engatwork-o.jpg" /></a>
</div>
</h3>
<p>I want to be one of them , so.. for you guys who don't know what Developer Advocate is , then check this out :</p>
<h3><span style="color: #000000; font-size: x-small;"> </span></h3>
<blockquote>
<h3>The area: Engineering</h3>
<p>Simply put, Google engineers make computers do amazing things.  Populated by extraordinarily creative, motivated and talented people,  our Engineering team gets excited by developing new applications that  really make a difference and are used by millions of people. We're  driven by Google's mission to organize the world's information and make  it universally accessible and useful. If you seek to tackle such  challenges as building a highly scalable computing infrastructure, novel  storage systems, innovative user experiences or the next big  application that will change the world, then this might be a perfect fit  for you.<!--more--></p>
<h3>The role: Developer Advocate</h3>
<p>As a Developer Advocate, you will be a member of the Developer  Relations organization. Developer Relations is focused on driving the  success of Google's developer products and the open web by creating a  thriving ecosystem of 3rd party applications and businesses built on  them. You will be an evangelist for our newest technologies in the  outside world, as well as a vocal advocate for developers' needs within  Google. We expect you to be an engineer who thrives on the cutting edge  of technology and loves seeing exciting, new applications and business  that other developers are building. Your job is to drive momentum for  exciting new technologies such as Chrome, Android, App Engine, Google  Wave, Google Maps API, HTML5 and our core Google Apps and Ads APIs. You  will work with some of our most strategic partners who push our  technology to its limits -- your job is to make them successful as they  build apps that showcase the potential of our APIs and developer  products. You will be the public face of Google representing these  products, speaking at conferences, on panels, at user groups, actively  blogging, tweeting and engaging with developer press and blogger</p>
<h4>Responsibilities:</h4>
<ul>
<li>Create momentum and drive the success of Google&rsquo;s developer products  and the open web through your interactions with 3rd party developers  building applications and businesses on them.</li>
<li>Advocate the adoption of Google developer products to strategic partners and the broader developer community.</li>
<li>Participate in technical and design discussions with technical  executives at strategic partners to speed adoption and ensure best  practices during implementation.</li>
<li>Evangelize our developer products in person and online by presenting  at conferences, blogging, writing technical tutorials and other similar  activities.</li>
<li>Advocate for developers internally, and influence Google developer  product strategy by working with Product Management, Engineering, PR,  Marketing, Business Development and other cross-functional teams.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Requirements:</h4>
<ul>
<li>BA/BS in Computer Science or a similar technical degree preferred.</li>
<li>Excellent public speaking skills and charisma, with experience presenting to large technical audiences.</li>
<li>Experience blogging and writing technical articles, ideally with an existing follower base.</li>
<li>Experience working directly with large partners or with press and bloggers preferred.</li>
<li>Considerable success as a software developer, architect, technology  evangelist, CTO or consultant working with web or mobile technologies.</li>
<li>Strong command of web application or mobile application development landscapes.</li>
<li>Solid programming abilities in one or more of the following languages: Java, PHP, Python, Ruby, .NET, JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>via <a href="http://goo.gl/BZPM">http://goo.gl/BZPM</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I want to be one of them , so.. for you guys who don't know what Developer Advocate is , then check this out : The area: Engineering Simply put, Google engineers make computers do amazing things. Populated by extraordinarily creative, motivated an...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu Oct 28 11:51:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu Oct 28 11:51:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>31835016</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>developer-advocate-at-google</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
