<item>
	<title>Captain Crunch needs your help</title>
	<link>http://www.opensecuritylab.org/captain-crunch-needs-your-help</link>
	<pubDate>Fri Dec 10 09:28:00 -0800 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Panggi Libersa Jasri Akadol]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Events"><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Security"><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.opensecuritylab.org/captain-crunch-needs-your-help</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-12-10/chrofqgDFgmdsDrgnaowlieCEjAIFCCBHilzFddBbxinJpCxfktzwoInwHGJ/JohnDraprBNK.JPG"><img alt="Johndraprbnk" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-12-10/chrofqgDFgmdsDrgnaowlieCEjAIFCCBHilzFddBbxinJpCxfktzwoInwHGJ/JohnDraprBNK.JPG" /></a>
</div>
</p>
<p>Official Site : <a href="http://savingcaptaincrunch.com">http://savingcaptaincrunch.com</a></p>
<p>When John Draper aka Captain Crunch is on form, great things happen. A  legendary hacker, he created the infamous Blue Box. He went on to  invent EasyWriter, the first ever word processor for the Apple II.</p>
<p>By any standard, he&rsquo;s an icon of the digital age.</p>
<h4><strong>But today, he&rsquo;s in great pain and risks losing the use of his hands and arms.</strong></h4>
<p>The problem started at the Def Con convention in late July of this  year, when an overzealous fan gave him a hug and Crunch immediately felt  a stabbing pain in his shoulders. The pain has worsened ever since. A  few critical nerves have been trapped and despite a program of physical  therapy and painkillers, Crunch&rsquo;s fingers and forearms are now  approaching total paralysis.</p>
<h4><strong>The situation is critical.</strong></h4>
<p>Crunch  is in such pain that he can barely put his shoes on in the  morning. One  of the pioneers of the Word Processor can barely type any  more, let  alone code. And the doctors have told him that within 3-6  months he  risks losing the use of his hands permanently because trapped  nerves die  after a while. But wait &ndash; there is some good news.</p>
<h4><strong>The Solution &ndash; Surgery</strong></h4>
<p>A straightforward surgical procedure can release the trapped nerves before they wither away, and return life to his hands.</p>
<p>The bad news is that Crunch cannot afford it. It costs $6,000 just  for the Medical co-pay for the surgery, $2,000 for the post-surgery  convalescence and even more for the drugs and physical therapy that will  get him back at his Mac and coding again.</p>
<h4><strong>Please give generously. Please spread the word.</strong></h4>
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Captain Crunch needs you.</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://savingcaptaincrunch.com/?page_id=136">
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Donate Here!!</h2>
</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Official Site : http://savingcaptaincrunch.com When John Draper aka Captain Crunch is on form, great things happen. A legendary hacker, he created the infamous Blue Box. He went on to invent EasyWriter, the first ever word processor for the Apple ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Fri Dec 10 09:28:00 -0800 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Fri Dec 10 09:28:00 -0800 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>35949557</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>captain-crunch-needs-your-help</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
